ach H. Pham

Faculty of Finance & Banking, HCMC Open University, Vietnam



💌 phamhoangthach@gmail.com | 🎢 thachpham.wordpress.com | 🖸 pham-hoang-thach | 🛅 phamhoangthach

2009-2010

2018-2023

I like collaborative environments where I can learn from my peers. I have worked in a variety of roles ranging from financial and data analyst to investment officer to researcher and lecturer. I am passionate about education and I believe that none of subject is too complex if the teacher is empathetic and willing to think of new approaches. In my PhD thesis, I have developed a framework for stock selection strategies based on mispricing and smart betas. This framework not only helps in explaining stock returns but also in evaluating the efficiency of stock markets and trading strategies. I am using Linux and free and open-source softwares. I prefer literate programming, reproducible research, and plain text.

Education

Victoria University Melbourne, Australia

PhD, Asset Pricing 2018-2023

University of Wollongong NSW, Australia

University of Economics HCMC HCMC, Vietnam

BEC, PLANNING AND INVESTMENT 2002-2006

Training

R, PYTHON, SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING, DATA VISUALIZATION

MCOM, FINANCE

O'Reilly, Linkedin Learning Online

Datastream, Refinitiv Eikon Melbourne, Australia

MACROECONOMIC INDICATORS AND FINANCIAL DATA TECHNOLOGY 2019-2020

Victoria University, Elservier Melbourne, Australia

LATEX, STATISTICS, RESEARCH WORKFLOW 2018-2020

EPICOR HCMC, Vietnam

ENTERPRISE RESOURCE PLANNING (ERP)

Thompson Reuters, Bloomberg HCMC, Vietnam

IBM HCMC, Vietnam

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPER OF E-BUSINESS APPLICATIONS 2006-2008

Achievements

TRADING SYSTEMS OF STOCKS AND BONDS

2018–2020 Joint Victoria University and Vietnam International Education Development PhD Scholarship (VIED, 911)

Tuition and Stipend Sponsorship

2020 Top 15% highest achieving students, Victoria University

outstanding academic achievements

Awarded for the

Tuition and Stipend 2021 Victoria University PhD Scholarship Sponsorship

> Awarded for the outstanding academic achievements

Excellent PhD Thesis 2023

Skills

- · Presentation, Research and Teaching
- Data Wrangling and Visualization
- Statistical and Financial Modeling
- Programming
- Version Control
- Linux and Open Source Software
- · Reporting and Writing
- Personal Knowledge Management and Personal Productivity



LATEX



Debian



Python



LaTeX zotero Zotero

Teaching

HCMC Open University

LECTURER

- Equity Analysis
- Fixed Income Analysis
- · Securities Analysis
- · Portfolio Management
- Financial Markets

Research Experience

Victoria University Melbourne, Australia

GRADUATE RESEARCHER

- Develop a framework for stock selection strategies based on mispricing and smart betas.
- Explain stock returns in both stock and portfolio levels
- Develop a new risk factor based on conditional Value-at-Risk
- · Measure market efficiency
- · Backtest trading strategies

University of Wollongong

GRADUATE RESEARCHER

• Financial Modeling & Valuation

- Portfolio Simulation & Asset Allocation
- Internal R&D Costs

Undergraduate Researcher

University of Economics HCMC

HCMC, Vietnam

NSW, Australia

HCMC, Vietnam

2012-Present

2018-2022

2005-2006

- · Conduct a research using cluster analysis to determine the main industries in Long An Province, Vietnam
- Operate a workshop of using multiple regression to determinate factors affecting gold prices in Vietnam
- Operate a workshop of linkage analysis (Input-Output Model)

Industry Experience _____

KPMG HCMC. Vietnam

Jun 2011–July 2012

Jul 2007-Sep 2008

CONSULTANT OF STRATEGIC COMMERCIAL INTELLIGENCE (SCI)

- Market Research
- · Story Board
- Dashboard
- Data Visualization
- Forecasting

ACB Securities (ACBS) HCMC, Vietnam

FINANCIAL ANALYST & ADVISOR

- · Stock Watch
- · Financial Modeling
- Valuation
- Writing Prospectus
- Public Offering & Private Placement Stocks & Bonds
- IPO & Auction Stocks
- · Listing Stocks on the Stock Exchanges

DongA Bank (DAB) HCMC, Vietnam DATA ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) 2006

· Collecting and analysing data of using ATM cards and real estate

Publications

Pham, T.H. (2023). Stock Selection for Trading Strategies Based on Risk Factors: A Study of The Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange. [PhD Thesis, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia].

Dương Quỳnh Nga, Phạm Hà, **Phạm Hoàng Thạch** (2022). *Quản lý danh mục đầu tư*. Tài liệu học tập. Đại học Mở Tp.HCM.

Pham, T.H., Wickremasinghe, G., Kulendran, N. (2022). An empirical study of the cross-section of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange (HSX) in Vietnam. Working Paper.

Pham, T.H., Wickremasinghe, G., Kulendran, N. (2022). An empirical study of multifactor asset pricing models on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange (HSX) in Vietnam. Working Paper.

Pham, T.H. (2019). A study of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange using ANOVA and multiple regressions. Working Paper.

Pham, T.H. (2018). An empirical study of the cross-section of stock returns on the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange. [Year 1 Thesis, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia].

Phạm Hoàng Thạch, Dương Quỳnh Nga (2018). *Quản lý danh muc đầu tư*. Slides bài giảng và video hướng dẫn môn hoc trưc tuyến. Đai hoc Mở Tp.HCM.

Phạm Hoàng Thạch (2006). Xác định các ngành công nghiệp chủ lực của tỉnh Long An [Luận văn đại học, Đại học Kinh tế Tp.HCM, Tp.HCM, Việt Nam].